KANDA BRANCH
（神田分行）
Yes! Our work is done for the day.
太好了 今天的稽核结束了
SPECIAL LUNCH SET / TEMPURA
（特色午餐、天妇罗）
There are so many nice restaurants.
好多看起来很好吃的餐厅
The chicken hot pot looked delicious too.
那个鸡肉锅看起来也很棒啊
I wish we came here during lunchtime.
如果能够午餐时间来这里就好了
Tempura, western style dishes, and… what?
天妇罗、西餐 还有…
No, Kanda is famous for soba.
不对 说到神田 当然是荞麦面啊
Hey, what are you doing? Hanasaki?
你干嘛呢 花琦？
Don't call my name.
别叫我的名字
That was so close.
好危险啊
Who is that man? Your friend?
你认识那个男的吗？
I don't know if I'd call him my friend, but…
也不能说认识 就是…
Your ex-boyfriend?
前男友？
Yes. I told you about him before.
对啊 之前跟你说过的那个
The civil servant two years older than you
就是那位在5月份分手的
who you broke up with last May.
比你大两岁的公务员
How do you remember all that?
你怎么记得那么清楚？
I didn't know that you're the type that hides when you run into your ex.
真没想到你是在街上遇见前男友 会躲起来的那种人呢
Yes, of course. It's uncomfortable.
当然会躲起来啊 通常都会觉得不舒服吧？
No, you should be able to say hi if you ended things in a nice way.
不 如果是和平分手的话 是可以笑着打招呼的
Oh? I remember you acting weird when you met your ex-wife.
你之前与前妻重逢的时候 还不是一脸尴尬？
Okay, you can tell me all about your
好吧 那我们今天就摸着酒杯
heartbreak today over a nice drink.
听你失恋的故事吧
No, thank you. I have an appointment tonight.
不用了 我今晚有事要做
What are you looking for?
找什么呢？
Nothing…
就那个…
That was close.
好危险
What are you doing?
你在干嘛啊？
It's all your fault for not keeping things organized.
又不是我的错 都怪你不好好整理
I know. Sorry.
是 抱歉
Free 30-minute shoulder massage for the working girl.
“给辛苦工作的女性放松肩颈 30分钟疗程免费券”
I was looking for this.
我就是找这个
I'm glad you're still here.
太好了 你们还在呢
Mr. Shibasaki.
芝崎次长
I want you to go to the Mitaka Branch right now.
我想请你们两个去一趟三老鹰分行
Now? But this expires today…
现在？可是这张券今天到期耶
What happened at the Mitaka Branch?
三鹰分行怎么了吗？
I just had a call.
我刚刚接到通知
They lost a promissory note from a customer.
有个客户寄放在银行的本票不见了
-What?
-什么？
They are searching for it right now.
他们的职员还在找呢
A promissory note has value.
本票是有价证券
It's the same as losing cash.
这跟遗失现金没什么两样
Yeah. But a promissory note is a piece of paper like this, right?
是啊 可是本票 就跟这张券差不多大小吧？
It'll be so difficult to find.
可不好找呢
It's not that simple. If it's really gone, it is going to be a big problem.
不仅如此 如果真的遗失的话就糟了
It will harm not only the branch but the entire bank.
这不止是分行的问题 而是关乎整间银行的信用
That's why headquarters want you to go and investigate it.
所以总部才想请你们去调查情况
And please help them find the promissory note, too.
帮他们找到那张本票
Okay.
好的
How much was that promissory note for?
那张本票的金额是多少啊？
Ten million yen.
一千万
Ten million yen?
-一千万？
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
MITAKA BRANCH
（东京第一银行三鹰分行）
All hands on deck, huh?
真的是全员都在找呢
You can't find it yet?
还没找到吗？
No.
还没有
BRANCH MANAGER HAJIME NOGUCHI
（分行经理 野口始）
It should be somewhere.
一定在某个地方
Listen. We must find it no matter what.
听好了 无论如何 一定要找出来
Yes, sir.
-是
Excuse me…
不好意思
You are?
你们是谁啊？
I am Soma from Branch Inspection at headquarters.
我是分行稽核班的相马
I am Hanasaki.
我是花琦
I see.
原来如此
I am Noguchi, the Branch Manager.
我是分行经理野口
I only called because I knew I had to report it.
我是出于义务才报告的
But I didn't need Branch Inspection to come.
不是想要劳烦你们分行稽核班
I understand.
我们理解
It is our job to understand the situation of the branches.
但是我们分行稽核班 有责任了解分行的情况
I was also told to help you find the promissory note.
上头也想派我们来协助寻找本票
It's not something Branch Inspection will be able to find that easily.
要是你们来了就能找到的话 我们就不用这么辛苦了
Please don't disturb us.
请你们不要妨碍到我们
Yes.
是
Branch Manager.
经理
I went to Kawabata Kikai and told them that we lost it.
我们去川端机械公司 报告了本票遗失的事
-How was it? -The President was very upset.
-怎么样？ -他们的社长非常生气
I can imagine that.
这也是在意料之中
I am sorry.
抱歉
Let me introduce them.
对了 这两位
They are from Branch Inspection at headquarters.
是总部分行稽核班的人
I am Koizumi, Chief of Finance.
我是融资课课长小泉
I am Hotta.
我是堀田
I am very sorry about all this.
真的是非常抱歉
He is the man that lost the promissory note.
就是这小子弄丢了本票
Right?
对吧？
-A promissory note was lost? -Yes.
-本票不见了？ -是的
It's the Mitaka Branch.
在三鹰分行
Mitaka Branch?
三鹰分行？
-I remember… -Yes.
-那不是… -没错
Yes. Branch Manager Noguchi is in the Doujima faction.
那里的分行经理野口是堂岛派的
I feel sorry for him.
遇上这种事真倒楣啊
-Kodama. -Yes.
-儿玉 -是
A lost promissory note will be a scandal that will hurt
遗失本票是会伤害到
the credibility of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
东京第一银行信用的丑闻啊
It is not the time to be talking about small issues like factions.
现在不是谈论派系这种小事的时候
I am very sorry.
真是十分抱歉
I hope they solve this problem.
希望这件事能够顺利解决
Just as I expected of Executive Director Shindo!
不愧是真藤常务
You see the bigger picture.
你这种放眼大局的想法
I am so impressed.
真是让人钦佩
Can you tell us the details of how this promissory note got lost?
能不能告诉我们本票遗失的经过？
Yes.
好的
I went to visit several customers this morning.
我今早拜访了好几家客户
I visited Kawabata Kikai at 11:30 a.m.
上午11点半去了川端机械公司
KAWABATA KIKAI
（川端机械）
I talked with President Kawabata about a loan.
我跟川端社长聊了贷款的事
And he gave me the promissory note before I left.
我离开前 交给了我一张本票
Did you put it in the collection envelope?
你有把本票放进收款袋吗？
Yes, I did.
有
I remember that for sure.
这点我很确定
What time did you leave Kawabata Kikai?
你是几点离开川端机械公司的？
I think it was around 12:30 p.m.
大概是12点半的时候
Then?
然後呢？
I came straight back to the branch.
然後 我就直接回分行了
Did you open your bag on the way?
途中有打开过包包吗？
Not even once.
没有
Then the promissory note should be in this branch, right?
那本票应该还在分行内部啊
Yes, it should be.
应该是这样的
What do you mean by "should be"?
“应该”是什么意思？
What about after you returned?
你回到分行之后做了什么？
Well…
是
I went to the Sales Department to process the promissory note
我去了营业课 想要处理本票
but the person in charge was out.
但是负责人不在
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
So I processed other deposits.
所以 我就先处理其他存款手续
Then I went to the Foreign Exchange Department for a money transfer.
然后 去了外币兑换课要求汇款
Thank you.
拜托了
I went to the Operation Department to register the online banking.
之后去了业务课帮客户注册网上银行
You visited so many places.
你去了这么多地方啊
While carrying ten million yen.
而且 手里还拿着一千万的本票
I am sorry.
真抱歉
The note could have fallen out in any of those places.
这样一来 那张本票可能掉在任何地方呢
What did you do after that?
那你之后做了什么？
I had a phone call when I returned to my seat.
我回到座位 接了一通电话
Hotta speaking.
我是堀田
Hello.
您好
Yes.
是
I see. I'll go there right away.
这样啊 我马上过去
I put the collection envelope in my desk.
我把收款袋放进抽屉里
And went out right away.
然后就出去了
Okay.
好了
When did you notice that it was missing?
你是什么时候发现本票不见的？
It was after 4 p.m.
是傍晚4点之后
I'm back.
辛苦了
I came back to the branch
我回到了分行
and opened the collection envelope to process it.
打开收款袋 想要处理本票
Just the promissory note was missing.
发现只有那张本票不见了
I looked everywhere right away.
我马上就开始到处找
But it was nowhere.
但是都找不到
Did you take it out by mistake when you were processing other things?
会不会是你从收款袋拿出其他东西时 不小心把本票一起拿出来了？
I don't think so.
应该不会
Then what?
所以是怎样？
The promissory note had feet and walked away by itself?
难道是本票长了脚 自己跑了吗？
But I really don't know where it could be.
但是 我真的没有印象
Do you understand this situation?
你到底搞清楚状况了吗？
This is an emergency.
这可不是件小事啊
If you can't find that note,
要是找不到那张本票
we will have to report it to the FSA and it's going to be a big scandal.
是必须要向金融厅报告的 这可是个大失误
I will have to take responsibility as Branch Manager.
身为分行经理的我是需要负责的
I am sorry.
对不起
When will Kawabata Kikai need the money?
川端机械公司希望什么时候交款？
Friday.
周五
We have to find it by tomorrow or we can't process it in time.
要是明天还找不到的话 就赶不及办手续了
-We must find it now. -Yes.
-总之 必须马上找到 -是
But we looked everywhere we could think of. Even the garbage cans.
但是 能找的地方都找了 甚至还翻了垃圾桶
Where else can we look?
还能上哪儿找呢？
I see.
也是
-Hanasaki? -What?
-花琦 -怎么了？
One of my colleagues once put a seal registration certificate
以前我有个同事不小心把印章证明书
through the shredder by mistake.
放进了碎纸机里呢
Shredder?
碎纸机？
Hanasaki, you don't have to talk about that now.
花琦 现在不是聊这事的时候吧？
I remember it was payday.
我记那天是发薪日
People make unbelievable mistakes when they are busy.
人一忙起来就会犯下离谱的错误
Don't say that.
说够了
But I guess that wouldn't happen…
但这次应该不会吧？
That's enough.
够了
I guess it's impossible to put a promissory note through a shredder.
应该不太可能把本票放进碎纸机吧？
Mr. Koizumi!
小泉课长
Yes!
是
You're always saying unnecessary things.
你总是这样说多余的话啊
Sorry.
对不起
This is from the Public Relations Department.
这些是涉外课的
That's a lot.
这么多
Here.
好了
Oh… Kasumi?
香澄姐
Mai!
小舞
What are you doing here?
你在干嘛呢？
I am in Branch Inspection now.
我现在在分行稽核班
I came because of the promissory note.
今天是为了本票的事来的
I see.
原来如此
I am in the PR Department here.
我现在在这里的涉外课
Hanasaki, do you know her?
花琦 是认识的人吗？
She was my senior when I was in the Akasaka Branch.
她是我在赤坂分行时的前辈
Ms. Kasumi Nishihara.
西原香澄
Hello, I'm Soma.
我是分行稽核班的相马
I am Nishihara.
我是西原
I am glad to see you, Kasumi. How have you been?
香澄姐 我好高兴再见到你啊
I've been doing well. You haven't changed at all.
-你还好吗？ -我很好 你还是跟以前一样呢
Let's get to work.
那我们开始吧
I haven't seen you in three years, ever since I moved to the Nakano Branch.
自从我调到中野分行之后 我们已经有三年没见了吧？
Has it been that long?
那么久了啊？
I ran into someone I didn't want to see, so I thought it was a bad day.
今天碰到一个不想见到的人 还以为是倒楣的一天呢
But it turned out to be a lucky day because I got to meet you.
但是 能再见到你 证明今天还是很幸运的
Move your hands.
别停下手啊
Sorry.
对不起
Why can't you find it?
究竟为什么会找不到？
Everyone.
各位
Are you sure you looked in every corner?
真的找遍每个角落了吗？
Hotta!
堀田
You caused huge trouble to the Mitaka Branch.
都是你给三鹰分行带来这么大的麻烦
One person's careless behavior
你一个人的粗心大意
puts an entire branch in crisis.
让分行全员都陷入了危机之中
How do you plan to make up for this?
你打算怎么补偿啊？
I am sorry.
真的十分抱歉
You shouldn't say…
你怎么能说…
Keep quiet.
闭嘴啦
Branch Manager. It's time…
野口经理 时间差不多了
I know.
我知道
If we stay here any longer,
如果继续找的话
it will affect business tomorrow.
会影响明天的工作
Please go home.
今天就到此为止 回家吧
Okay.
-是
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦大家了
I will see you tomorrow.
明天还要麻烦各位
See you tomorrow.
-辛苦了
It's so late.
那么晚了
Today was my daughter's birthday.
今天是我女儿的生日呢
-My wife's going to be mad. -I am sorry.
-我老婆肯定要生气了 -很抱歉
I am very sorry.
真的很抱歉
You also have a wife waiting for you at home.
你家也有妻子在等着呢
So you know how they feel.
你应该了解他们的心情吧
Yes.
是
I don't want to take responsibility as a Branch Manager for something
这么荒唐的事情 还想要让分行经理承担责任
stupid like this.
开什么玩笑？
If we can't find the note,
如果找不到那张本票
you will have to take responsibility for it.
就由你为此承担责任
-Hey! -With all due respect…
-喂 -恕我直言
Oh, no…
真是的
How the promissory note came to be lost is not clear yet.
本票遗失的经过和原因都还没搞清楚
Before holding Mr. Hotta accountable,
与其追究堀田先生的责任
thinking of ways to find the note should be our priority.
不如想办法找回本票 才是现在的优先事项吧？
What?
什么？
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
Cheers! We worked hard today.
-辛苦了
Mai, you haven't changed at all.
小舞 你还真是没有变啊
You spoke out to the Branch Manager in Akasaka too.
在赤坂分行的时候 她也是像那样跟经理说话的
I know. Dad, do you remember Kasumi?
没错 爸 你还记得香澄姐吗？
Yes, of course.
当然记得了
You were the number one teller in Akasaka that everyone wanted to marry.
香澄可是赤坂分行票选 男性最想娶回家的柜员第一名呢
That's not true.
没那回事啦
This is from me, Kasumi.
这是请你吃的
Eggplant sashimi.
水茄子生鱼片
-It looks delicious. -It's for Kasumi.
-看起来好好吃啊 -这是给香澄的
You are too nice to beautiful women.
你对美女的招待果然不一样啊
-So Ms. Nishihara, you were a teller? -Yes.
-西原小姐也是前任柜员吗？ -是的
She was my mentor when I entered the bank.
香澄姐是我刚进银行时的导师呢
-Are you okay? -Sorry.
-你还好吗？ -不好意思
She taught me everything about the bank from scratch.
她从基础开始 教会了我所有银行的业务
Thank you very much.
谢谢你
I see. Then Hanasaki is who she is today because of Ms. Nishihara.
原来如此 那么 能有今天的花琦 都是多亏了西原小姐啊
Yes. I admire her.
没错 她可是我的偶像
Mai, you are too nice.
小舞 你说得太夸张了啦
I mean it.
我是说真的
I miss the days when we worked together as tellers.
真是怀念一起当柜员的那段日子啊
Do you remember our leader, Ms. Yamada?
你还记得当时的山田主任吗？
She's getting married.
听说她结婚了呢
Really? That old bossy-pants?
那个专横霸道的主任吗？
You never know what will happen.
真是想都没想过啊
Do you plan to marry?
那你结婚了吗？
I broke up with my boyfriend recently.
最近才刚和男朋友分手了呢
Me too.
我也是呢
Really? Did you break up?
你也分手了吗？
Yes, her relationships never last.
是啊 她没有一段感情是长久的
Dad, keep quiet.
爸 你别乱说啦
I never thought of marrying him anyway.
不过 我也没想过要嫁给他
I see.
这样啊
-Let's drink tonight. -Sure.
-好 今晚就不醉不归吧 -来
Kasumi.
香澄
-Eat this and cheer up. -Again?
-吃这个 打起精神来 -又来了
I love deep-fried tofu.
我最喜欢炸豆腐了
I am glad to hear that. You know what?
那太好了 对了
I'll bring out the homemade pickled squid.
我把自制的腌鱿鱼也拿出来吧
He is serving us so many dishes today.
今天怎么有上不完的菜色啊？
Oh well.
就是啊
By the way, I wonder where the promissory note went.
话说回来 本票到底跑到哪去了呢？
Yeah. It's going to be a serious problem if we can't find it by tomorrow.
是啊 要是明天还找不到的话 麻烦可就大了
Right.
是啊
First, we have to ask the remitter to issue an accident report to the bank.
首先 要去拜托出票人 请他向银行提交事故申请
Then Kawabata Kikai will report the loss to the police
然后 川端机械公司需要向警察报失
and go to the court for a public notification process.
再向法院申述公示通告…
My head is hurting just hearing all that.
光是用听的 我的头就痛了
There is no doubt that we received the promissory note, so we must
事实上 我们确实收下了那张本票
deposit ten million yen to Kawabata Kikai on Friday.
所以到了周五 银行必须向川端机械公司汇入一千万
Our bank must pay the ten million yen in place of the remitter
总之 找到本票之前 银行就必须代替出票人
until we find the promissory note.
偿还那一千万的债务
That's going to be trouble.
这可是个大麻烦啊
That's why it's somewhat understandable for Branch Manager Noguchi
所以 也难怪野口经理
to worry about taking responsibility.
那么害怕承担责任
But he shouldn't have talked like that.
但他也不能说那种话啊
Kasumi, tell me about Mr. Hotta.
香澄姐 堀田先生是个怎样的人啊？
Yes?
嗯？
I understand that it's his mistake.
我知道堀田先生有错
But I feel sorry for him.
但是 我总觉得他很可怜
Right.
是啊
Mr. Hotta is a little unreliable.
虽然堀田不是很沉稳的那种人
But he is serious about his job, and he'd never do anything irresponsible.
但他对工作很认真 不是马马虎虎的人
I see.
这样啊
-Okay. -You came up with an idea?
-很好 -你又想做什么？
Mr. Soma. Let's trace his steps.
相马 我们去重走堀田先生的路线吧
Steps?
重走？
Let's inspect every step he took starting at
从他在川端机械公司那里 收下本票开始
Kawabata Kikai where he received the note,
到发现本票遗失之前
until the moment he realized that it was lost.
我们查证一下他去过的每个地方吧
The clues are at the scene.
不是都说线索就在现场吗？
Let's do it.
好 就这么决定了
We are not the police, you know.
我们又不是警察
Therefore, we will be requiring Mr. Hotta's help.
总之 我们想请堀田先生帮一下忙
Retrace his steps?
重走路线吗？
I don't think you'll find it by doing that.
我不觉得这样就能找到本票
Me neither.
就是说啊
It's no use.
没用的
People at headquarters seem to have a lot of time.
看来 总部的人真的很闲啊
With all due respect…
恕我…
I understand what you are saying,
我理解你的意思
but we have to make sure we cover all bases with situations like this.
但是 我们必须仔细处理这种情况
Okay, then.
那好吧
I can't assign important jobs to Hotta
反正在找到本票之前
until we find the promissory note anyway.
也不能把重要的工作交给堀田
Thank you for your support.
-十分感谢
Hi, Kasumi.
香澄
Do you know if they found the promissory note?
昨天那本票的事情怎么样了？
They haven't found it yet.
还没找到呢
Do we have to stay late to look for it again?
今天会不会又要留下来继续找啊？
I have a date today.
我今天有约会呢
This is such a hassle.
真麻烦啊
Right.
是啊
I am going out.
我出去了
KAWABATA KIKAI
（川端机械）
Headquarters?
总部？
What is headquarters doing here when you haven't
本票都还没找到
even found the promissory note yet?
你们总部的人来干嘛？
We understand that this is a serious problem.
我们了解事态的严重性
I would like to ask for time to confirm the details.
所以 想来找你确认详情
What if someone else finds it…
万一在你们问这些的时候…
PRESIDENT OF KAWABATA KIKAI
（川端机械社长 川端道和）
…and abuses it while you're going about asking questions.
…本票被谁捡去滥用 那要怎么办？
-I am not responsible for this. -I'm sorry.
-到时不会要我们负责吧？ -十分抱歉
I don't care if you find the promissory note or not.
我才不管你们找不找得到本票
I just need you to deposit the money.
只要有钱汇进来就好
Ten million yen by Friday.
周五 一千万
I can't manage the operation if the payment is delayed.
要是延迟了 我们公司就无法营业了
We will handle the situation so that it will not affect your business.
我们会尽快处理好这件事 不给你造成麻烦的
We want to do our best to find the promissory note for now.
所以 现在必须尽力找到本票的下落
So, what do you want to know?
那你们要问什么？
May I confirm that Hotta visited here at 11:30 a.m. yesterday?
请问昨天堀田先生拜访的时间 是11点半吧？
Let me see.
我看看啊
The appointment was 11:30 a.m.
约定时间是11点半
He talked about the loan, received the promissory note,
他与你讨论了贷款 并收下本票后
and he left here at 12:30 p.m. Am I right?
在12点半离开了 对吗？
I don't remember the exact time.
确切的时间不记得了
-Is there something wrong? -I remember…
-怎么了吗？ -对了
Another person visited me at noon yesterday.
昨天中午还有一个来访者呢
You saw him come in as you were leaving, right?
你离开的时候 刚好有个人进来了 你记得吧？
Yes.
是的
What time did he come?
他是什么时候来的？
He came at 12 p.m. as promised.
在约定好的12点准时到的
Then you left here at 12 p.m.?
所以你是12点就离开了吗？
Why did you lie to us?
为什么你要撒谎？
I'm sorry.
对不起
You left here at 12 p.m.
你是12点离开的
And what time did you get back to the branch?
回到分行又是几点？
Around 1 p.m.
1点左右
It shouldn't take more than 15 minutes to get to the branch.
从这里直接回分行的话 不用15分钟
Where did you go?
你到底去哪里了？
-I went to a diner. -A diner?
-我去了家庭餐厅 -家庭餐厅？
I was having a cup of coffee.
我去喝了杯咖啡
Why didn't you tell us that you went to a diner?
那你之前为什么不跟我们说 去了家庭餐厅的事？
Um… well…
这个…
I didn't want people to know that I was slacking off.
我不想被人知道自己在偷懒
I'm sorry.
所以才…
Just because of that?
就是这个原因吗？
I am sorry.
对不起
-Mr. Soma. -Yeah?
-相马 -嗯？
Let's go to that diner right now.
我们现在去那间家庭餐厅吧
Okay.
好的
We want to check and see if we left something here yesterday.
我们想问问看 这里有没有我们遗失的物件
Sure.
好的
It's something like this.
是像这样的东西
No, we didn't find anything like that here.
抱歉 我们没捡到这样的东西
I see.
这样啊
May I check the table he used yesterday?
我们可以看看他昨天坐过的位子吗？
But there are customers sitting at that table right now.
但是 那个位子现在有客人呢
I understand. But may I please take a look?
请你一定要帮个忙
Please.
拜托了
I am very sorry to interrupt your lunch.
很抱歉打扰你们用餐
It's not here.
果然不在这里呢
I didn't open my bag here even once.
我在这里的时候 没打开过包包
I don't think it's here.
应该不在这里吧？
Just in case.
只是以防万一啊
Just in case!
以防万一
Whose fault does he think this is…
他以为这是谁的错啊？好痛
I will process the fixed deposit amount as soon I get back.
我一回去 就会为你的定期存款办手续
-Thanks. -Sure.
-拜托了 -好的
Come on, Hanasaki. It wouldn't have fallen along the street.
拜托啦 花琦 怎么可能会掉在路上呢？
Just in case.
以防万一嘛
Do you remember anything?
你想起什么了吗？
Yes.
是的
I bought a bottle of tea from this vending machine.
我在这个自动贩卖机买过茶
Did you open your bag at that time?
那时候打开包包了吗？
No, I have my wallet right here.
没有 我的钱包在这里
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
We couldn't find any clues.
结果 还是没有头绪啊
You were so hyped up when we started.
你一开始不是还干劲十足的吗？
Mr. Hotta. There's nothing else you're hiding, right?
堀田先生 你真的没什么瞒着我们的吧？
There's nothing. I'm sorry.
没有了 对不起
Can you think of anything else?
你有想到什么线索吗？
Anything else?
线索？
For example, does someone have a grudge against you?
比如 有谁对你怀恨在心吗？
A grudge…
怀恨在心？
Someone in the branch stole…
是被分行的人偷了…
You're too loud, you idiot. I said, "for example."
你太大声了啦 笨蛋 我只是打个比方
We did everything but couldn't find it.
都做到这个地步了 还是没找到
Someone could be bullying him.
有可能是遭人报复了
But who would do such a thing?
但谁会这么做呢？
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Nothing.
没什么
Um…
那个…
I will take responsibility for this.
这次的事 我会负责的
Responsibility?
负责？
How would you do that?
你要怎么负责？
I will reimburse ten million yen myself.
我会自行赔偿那一千万
How will you get that money?
那么大一笔钱 你要怎么赔？
I will sell the land that my grandfather left me.
我会卖掉爷爷留给我的土地
I will also use my savings
然後用我的存款
and pay the rest from my salary every month.
和每个月的薪资偿还余款
I'll pay no matter how long it takes.
不管花多长时间也要赔
Then it would be the same as finding the promissory note, right?
这么做 跟找到本票是一样的吧？
That's not…
这个…
No, it wouldn't be the same.
是不一样的
The promissory note was lost.
本票遗失了
This problem won't be solved even if you pay for it.
不是你赔偿就可以解决的问题
Please don't misunderstand.
请不要误会
The banking business is not that simple.
银行的业务不是那么简单的事
You say you will pay by yourself because you lost it?
你说你弄丢了 可以用自己的钱赔偿
That's the same as using your customer's money.
这跟动用客户的钱是一样的
It is something that a banker should never do.
都是银行职员绝对不能做的事
This is preposterous!
岂有此理？
You were at a diner
你是说你拿着一千万的本票
with a promissory note for ten million yen?
在家庭餐厅偷懒吗？
I am sorry.
十分抱歉
Koizumi, isn't this your fault for not training him well enough?
小泉课长 就是因为你疏于管理监督 才会发生这种事
I am sorry.
我很抱歉
We don't have time.
已经到期限了
We have no choice but to pay ten million yen for now.
只能先由我们银行偿还一千万了
This is unprecedented.
这种事是前所未有的
I am sorry.
对不起
This is no longer a problem just within Mitaka Branch.
这已经不是三鹰分行的内部问题了
It is a big scandal that affects the entire Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
这可是影响到 东京第一银行全体的大丑闻
Your responsibility is serious.
这个责任太严重了
After all that you've done, you won't have a place here anymore.
事情变成这样 这里已经没有你的立足之处了
Be prepared to be transferred.
做好被调遣的准备吧
Oh, no… a transfer…
不会吧？调遣？
If someone has to take responsibility for this,
如果需要有人为此负责的话
it should be me.
那必须是我
It can't be helped.
调遣也是没办法的
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
You worked so hard.
真是辛苦你们了啊
Here you go.
辛苦了
-Thank you.
-谢谢
We walked and looked everywhere but it was all in vain.
我们去遍了那些地方查看 却一无所获
When he mentioned the diner, I was so sure it'd be there.
他提到家庭餐厅的时候 我还想说肯定在那边呢
A diner…
家庭餐厅啊
I used to go there often to slack off when I stepped out
我以前出去见客户的时候
to meet customers.
也常在那里偷懒呢
Really?
真的假的？
Yes. When I got tired after visiting customers,
是啊 每次拜访好几家客户 很累的时候
I craved something sweet
就很想吃点甜的
like parfait and cake…
像是冷糕、蛋糕之类的
I see. That's why.
所以才这样
I also stopped by diners all the time when I was working for a company.
我还是公司职员时 也经常去呢
You too, Dad?
你也是吗？
Yes. There are many businessmen that go to diners.
是啊 去家庭餐厅的公司职员可多了
There are counter seats
店里也有这样的吧台
so we can be at ease when it's busy.
人多的时候也不怕占位子
You are right.
没错
We can get along, Mr. Shibasaki.
我们真是投缘啊 芝崎次长
How about a drink?
花琦爸爸 你也来一杯吧
That's nice. I got some good sake in today.
好啊 今天刚好进了些好酒
-All of these. -Which one should I choose?
-就是这些 -喝哪个好呢？
I recommend this.
我推荐这个
Dad, don't drink too much.
爸 别喝多了
Seat at a counter…
吧台啊…
What's wrong, Mr. Soma?
怎么了吗？
Mr. Hotta said that he went to the diner around noon, right?
堀田先生说 他是中午去那间家庭餐厅的吧？
Yes. It was a little past 12 p.m.
对 好像是刚过12点
The diner should be busy around that time.
那应该是很多客人的时间呢
But Mr. Hotta sat at a table for four by the window.
可是 堀田先生却坐在窗边的四人卡座
That's kind of bold…
那脸皮得很厚才行啊
Or he wasn't by himself.
又或者说 他不是一个人去的
That's very likely.
这个可能性很大
I assumed he was alone when he said that he slacked off at a diner.
他说自己在家庭餐厅偷懒 我们就认为他一定是一个人
Mr. Hotta might have met someone at the diner.
如果他在那里遇到别人的话
That person may know about the promissory note.
那个人也许会知道本票的事
-Let's ask Mr. Hotta. -Hey, wait a second.
-我们问问堀田先生吧 -等等 先别着急啊
Mr. Hotta has been trying to hide that from us.
他之前还一直瞒着我们呢
He may not tell us the truth even if we ask him.
就算问他的话 他可能也不会说实话
You are right.
确实
Let's go to the diner again tomorrow.
好 我们明天再去一趟那间家庭餐厅
You're fired up, Mr. Soma.
你也是干劲十足啊 相马
Not really.
没有啊
-Two coffees, please. -Okay.
-两杯咖啡 谢谢 -好的
Do you remember the customer who sat at that table around noon two days ago?
请问你记得前天中午 坐在那个卡座的客人吗？
This is what he looks like.
就是这个人
-No, I don't remember. -I see.
-我没印象 -这样啊
Excuse me. Do you remember this customer?
不好意思 请问你记得这位客人吗？
He came here around noon two days ago.
他在前天中午光顾过
I have no idea.
我不记得了
I see.
这样啊
They don't remember every customer's face.
果然没办法记得每个客人啊
Makes sense.
是啊
-Excuse me. -Hey.
-不好意思 -喂…
Do you remember…
请问你记不记得…
I'm sorry, but they are working.
不好意思 我们在工作呢
I am very sorry.
真对不起
We got nothing. I thought we'd be able to find something.
完全不行啊 我还以为能找到什么线索呢
Of course not. We are not the police.
没办法啊 我们又不是警察
Excuse me.
不好意思
You never give up.
没学乖呢
This is a man who sat by the window at lunch two days ago.
这是前天中午 坐在那个窗边卡座的男客人
May I ask if you remember him?
请问你记得他吗？
-Yes. I remember him. -Really?
-喔 记得啊 -真的吗？
-Yes. -Was he alone?
-是的 -他自己一个人来的吗？
No. He was with a woman.
不是 还有一个女人
A woman?
女人？
He got a phone call while he was meeting with that woman.
他们见面的时候 这个男的还接到一通电话
A phone call?
一通电话？
He went out to talk for a while.
他出去外面接听了
I remember very well because the woman looked really sad.
那个女的看起来很失落 所以我记得很清楚
Then he must have left his bag when he went to take the call.
那他接电话的时候 公事包肯定留在座位上
Can you describe that woman?
那位女客人长什么样？
She seemed to be in her thirties…
我想想啊 大概三十几岁
She was wearing a black jacket.
穿著一件黑色外套
It might be a uniform.
好像是制服
Uniform?
制服？
She was wearing an orange scarf.
颈项还围着橘色的丝巾
That's our uniform, isn't it?
那是我们的制服吧？
No doubt about it.
应该是的
Mr. Hotta was meeting someone from the branch.
所以堀田先生见了分行的某个人
But why is he hiding it?
但是 为什么要隐瞒呢？
There must be a reason why he can't tell us.
一定是有不可告人的理由吧？
We need to know who he was meeting.
我们需要知道他见的是谁
But how can we do that?
但是 要怎么查呢？
Ah… how about the business log?
业务日志
We may find out who it was by looking at the business log.
查看前天的业务日志 说不定能知道什么
That's a good idea.
好主意
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK MITAKA BRANCH
（东京第一银行三鹰分行）
Let's check for someone who went to the southeast area
我们要查看堀田先生 在家庭餐厅的12点到1点之间
from 12 p.m. to 1 p.m. while Mr. Hotta was at the diner.
同样前往东南区的人
Or someone who didn't report anything during that time.
或者这段时间没有记录的人
Employees of the PR Department and Sales Department
穿那个制服的部们是涉外课
all wear uniforms.
还有营业课
I should check their lunch time and the customer visitation records.
那我看看他们的午休时间 以及客户拜访记录
Monday… around noon in the southeast area.
周一 大概12点 东南区
There is no one.
没有呢
I found it, Hanasaki.
我找到了 花琦
Just one person.
只有一个人
12:40 - SOUTHEAST
（12点40分 东南）
Kasumi Nishihara?
西原香澄？
Why did Kasumi meet Mr. Hotta?
香澄姐为什么和堀田先生见面？
I don't know.
为什么呢？
She didn't mention it at all.
她也没提到过这件事
Maybe…
难道…
-Do you plan to marry? -No.
那你结婚了吗？
I broke up with my boyfriend recently.
最近才刚和男朋友分手了呢
I never thought of marrying him anyway.
不过 我也没想过要嫁给他
No… it can't be…
不会吧？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I just thought that maybe they're in a relationship.
我想说他们会不会在交往
But Mr. Hotta is married, so it can't be.
可是 堀田先生已经结婚了啊 应该不可能吧？
An affair, huh…
婚外情啊
That would explain why Mr. Hotta tried to hide the fact that he met up with her.
这样就能解释为什么堀田先生 要隐瞒跟她见面的事了
Banks are strict with office romances.
银行对办公室恋情很严格
He could get a disciplinary action for something like an affair.
如果被发现是婚外情的话 可能会受到处分
Oh, no…
天啊
Let's go back to the diner and confirm.
我们回去家庭餐厅确认一下吧
Mr. Hotta.
堀田先生
Yes?
有什么事吗？
I want to ask you something.
我们有件事想问你
Yes.
好的
You were not alone at the diner that day.
你那天不是自己一个人去家庭餐厅的
You met a woman.
你在那里见了一个女人
That woman is Ms. Kasumi Nishihara, right?
而那个女人就是西原香澄 对吧？
I confirmed it at the diner.
我们向家庭餐厅的店员确认过了
Yes. They were here.
没错 就是他们
Why didn't you tell us that?
你为什么不告诉我们？
Mr. Hotta. What kind of relationship do you have with her?
堀田先生 你们两是什么关系？
Please tell us the truth.
请告诉我们实话
I was in a relationship with Ms. Nishihara.
我和西原交往过
Would you tell us everything?
可以请你从实招来吗？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Kasumi.
香澄姐
You met up with Mr. Hotta that day, right?
你那天见过堀田先生了 对吧？
You had an affair with him.
你跟他有婚外情 对吧？
Why did you have an affair with him?
为什么要搞婚外情呢？
You know that Mr. Hotta has a wife.
你明知道堀田先生是有家室的人
Why?
为什么？
You may not understand, Mai.
小舞你可能无法理解吧？
But you can't control loving someone.
喜欢上一个人是身不由己的
Our relationship started two years ago.
我们的关系是在两年前开始的
I knew that he was married, of course.
我也清楚他已经是有妇之夫
But that didn't bother me.
但我并不在意
I was happy just being with him.
只要能跟他在一起 我就很幸福了
Did Mr. Hotta tell you that he would divorce his wife?
是不是堀田先生说过 他会和妻子离婚？
No.
没有
He's not someone that would make promises he can't keep.
他不是会随便做出承诺的人
And I didn't
而且
want to break up his family either.
我也不想破坏他的家庭
Then…
那么
why did you steal the note?
你为什么要偷走本票呢？
You stole the promissory note from him, didn't you?
那张本票是你拿走的 对吧？
Two days ago…
前天
He said he had to tell me something important.
他说有件重要的事要告诉我
To tell you the truth…
其实
My wife is pregnant.
我老婆怀孕了
I'm sorry, but…
抱歉 但是…
I want to end this.
我想结束这段关系
He always told me that
他总是告诉我
he was in a loveless marriage with his wife.
他和妻子的关系早已经很冷淡
That he hasn't slept with her in years.
好几年都没有一起睡了
Of course, a man having an affair would say something like that.
当然了 搞婚外情的男人总是说这种话
But that was my source of comfort.
但这种话能让我心里好过一点
That's why I was able to believe that he loved me more than his wife.
这样我才会相信 他爱我比爱他的妻子多
But his wife got pregnant.
但他的妻子居然怀孕了
It was a horrible betrayal.
这简直是残酷的背叛
His wife called him while he was breaking up with me.
在谈分手的途中 他的妻子打了电话给他
That's when I thought that
那时我想
I wanted to get him into trouble.
我要让他惹上大麻烦
So I opened his bag.
于是我打开了他的公事包
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
Then I found a promissory note for ten million yen.
然后 我看到一张一千万的本票
I thought he would be in serious trouble if he lost it.
如果弄丢了这个 他一定会相当困扰吧？
It was just that and nothing more.
我的意图真的只是这样
I didn't think that it would become this big.
我没想到会引起这样的轩然大波
I couldn't forgive him.
我真的无法原谅他
I was the only one who got hurt.
受伤的只有我
I couldn't forgive him for going back home to his
他却能一副事不关己的样子
wife and child as if nothing had ever happened.
回到老婆孩子的身边 我真的没办法原谅
I couldn't forgive him.
没办法原谅
Even so…
所以
You were hurt, but does that
你自己受了伤
justify everything?
就能为所欲为了吗？
I also can't forgive Mr. Hotta for trampling over your feelings.
我也不能原谅堀田先生 那样践踏你的感情
However…
可是
you taught me what it means to be a banker.
是你教会了我银行职员的意义
Yet…
这样的你
you let your emotions get the best of you and did something wrong.
居然因为一时的冲动做出这种事
It…
你这么做…
It is so wrong.
你这么做是不对的
I am disqualified as a banker.
我不配当银行职员
No wonder you are mad at me.
也难怪你会生气
I am not mad at you.
我不是生气
I am sad.
我是伤心
Kasumi, you taught me that
香澄姐 还记得你曾告诉我
we're not only holding onto our customer's money.
我们不止握着顾客的钱财
We're holding onto their trust as well.
还握着他们的信任
You said that our job
你说我们的工作
is to make our customers happy.
是能让顾客感到幸福的工作
You taught me that,
说这些话的香澄姐
but you did something that a banker should never do.
却做了银行职员最不应该做的事情
So I am sad.
所以我很伤心
I understand that no one can
我明白喜欢上一个人的心
stop you from loving someone.
任谁也无法阻止
But…
但是
I wish I had become your confidant
如果我能在事情发展到这个地步之前
before all of this came to be.
成为你诉说心事的对象 或许这一切就不会发生了
I am who I am today all thanks to you.
我之所以有今天 也是多亏了你的教诲
So…
所以
I wish I could have stopped you.
我真的很希望能阻止你做这些事
I…
我
I did a stupid thing.
做了件傻事呢
I was so stupid.
我真是个笨蛋啊
I have been working so hard for eight years.
我尽心尽力工作了八年
But I ruined everything by doing this.
却因为这件事全毁了
Kasumi…
香澄姐
I'm sure Mr. Hotta told you
一定是堀田跟你们说
that he suspects me.
他怀疑是我拿走的吧？
I can't blame him.
也不能怪他呢
He has people to protect.
他有需要守护的人
You are wrong.
不是的
You are wrong about that.
不是这样的
Mr. Hotta never said that he suspects you.
堀田先生他…从来没有怀疑过你
He keeps saying that you have nothing to do with the promissory note.
他还一直说你跟本票遗失的事 一点关系都没有
No way.
骗人
You are lying.
骗人 怎么可能？
No, she's not.
她没有骗你
Mr. Hotta told us that
堀田先生确实跟我们说了
he was with you at the diner on that day
那天和你在家庭餐厅见面的事
and that he was having an affair with you.
还承认了你们的婚外情
But he kept on saying that
但他始终坚持
losing the promissory note is all his fault,
本票会遗失都是他的错
and that you had nothing to do with it.
与你没有任何关系
I didn't answer any phone calls that time.
我当时根本没有接听过什么电话
I didn't leave my seat when I met with her.
跟她见面时 也没有离开过座位
So she couldn't have stolen the promissory note from me.
所以 她是不可能偷走本票的
I lost it.
是我弄丢的
It is all my fault. Just myself.
所有的责任全都在我一人
Mr. Hotta most likely knew what you had done.
堀田先生应该早就知道是你做的
And yet…
即便如此
he tried to take all the responsibility by himself.
他还是愿意负起所有的责任
There is one more thing.
还有一点
An office affair is a scandal that can end a baker's career.
办公室婚外情对银行职员来说 是致命的丑闻
He would be punished,
他会受到处分
and he won't be promoted.
也不会再有晋升的机会
But Mr. Hotta readily admitted the affair.
但堀田先生却连这点都承认了
Because he wanted to protect you.
这都是因为他想守护你
Kasumi.
香澄姐
I don't know much about romance.
恋爱的事我不太懂
But what he did for you…
但堀田先生为你做的事
that's Mr. Hotta's true feelings for you.
已经表达了他真正的心意
I don't think his love for you was a lie.
我认为他对你的感情是真心诚意的
I am sorry.
对不起
I was overwhelmed with guilt.
我因为罪恶感 不知该如何是好
I am glad that you found it.
被小舞你揭开真相 真是太好了
PROMISSORY NOTE
（本票一千万）
Mr. Hotta.
堀田先生
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
The loss of the promissory note at Mitaka Branch has come to a close.
三鹰分行的本票遗失一事已经结案了
Yes. Ms. Kasumi Nishihara received a disciplinary dismissal.
是的 西原香澄小姐被解雇了
Mr. Hotta was transferred to another branch.
堀田先生则是被调到其他分行
This put a big X-mark on his career.
这件事算是 给他的职业生涯沾上了污点呢
Although there was no practical damage to Kawabata Kikai,
虽说这次的事 没有对川端机械造成实质的伤害
he caused them a lot of trouble.
但确实是给客户造成了麻烦
He brought this upon himself.
这也没办法啊
But I still can't believe that Kasumi did such a thing.
我还是不敢相信 香澄姐居然会做那种事
Anyone can fall into temptation.
任何人都有鬼迷心窍的时候
She was probably planning to return it secretly, but she couldn't
她可能是想事后偷偷还回来的
because it became a huge issue.
却没想到事情闹得那么大
Branch Manager Noguchi received an admonition.
野口经理已被予以警告
Not one word leaked to the media,
这件事媒体完全不知道
so we avoided damaging the reputation of our bank.
所以避免了损害银行的名声
Branch Inspection does something good once in a while.
分行稽核班偶尔也会做些好事呢
Ouch!
好痛
That's good news.
那真是太好了
Senior Executive Director Doujima must be really relieved too.
想必堂岛专务也松了一口气吧？
It was about to become a big scandal for the Doujima faction.
差一点就演变成堂岛派的大丑闻了呢
I am so glad.
真是太好了呢
Excuse me.
我先出去了
Branch Inspection.
是 这里是分行稽核班
Yes.
是
A guest for me?
有客人找我吗？
Ms. Nishihara?
西原小姐？
I'm sure you heard that I was fired.
你应该听说我被银行解雇了吧？
Yes.
是
It's no surprise since I did something worthy of a dismissal.
我做了那种事情 这也是理所当然的
What are you going to do?
那你接下来有什么打算？
I am thinking of going to a business school
我想去商学院
to study accounting.
学学会计
Once I get the qualification, I want to find a job to put that to use.
只要取得执照 就能找个会计方面的工作了
I see.
原来如此
I have been saving money,
我一直有在存钱
so I think I am okay for a while.
所以 生活暂时不成问题
The truth is,
其实啊
I had been saving money because I was prepared to pay the compensation
我一直在想 如果堀田他离了婚 需要支付前妻赡养费的话
for Mr. Hotta's place in case he ever divorced his wife.
我可以帮他出那笔钱 所以才一直存到现在的
I was stupid.
我很傻 对吧？
I said that I wasn't expecting anything, but I was trying to get everything.
嘴上说不奢望什么 却想办法把一切都弄到手
So I will use all that money to get rid of my past self
现在我会利用这笔钱 把从前的自己删掉
and reset myself.
重新开始
I'm hoping I can do that.
不过 不知道做不做得到呢
I'm sure you can do it, Kasumi. Do your best.
你一定可以的 要加油哦
Thank you.
谢谢你
Take care of yourself.
那你也要保重
Thanks. You too.
好 你也是
-She's a good woman. -Mr. Soma.
-真是个好女人呢 -相马
Okay. It's time to reset. We have an inspection to go to.
好了 打起精神 我们有稽核工作了
We're heading to Sendai.
这次要去仙台
Sendai is beef tongue, but is that too boring?
仙台的话就是牛舌 但是不是没什么新意啊？
Hiyashi Chuka is delicious right now.
不 这季节当然要吃日式凉面啊
We can have Hiyashi Chuka for lunch if we go now. Let's go.
现在出发的话 午餐就能去餐厅吃日式凉面 走吧
Wait, Hanasaki.
等等 花琦
Where is your bag?
你的包包呢？
But you don't have your bag, either.
你也没带公事包啊
-It's not like me. -Let's go.
-我也忘了啊 -快走
Destroy our bank?
毁掉银行？
Someone posted it online.
有人在网上留言
Hey Branch Inspection!
-灭火器呢？ -分行稽核班
Weren't you on watch?
你们不是在监视吗？
What happened?
到底是怎么回事？
Tokyo Daiichi Bank killed him.
是东京第一银行杀了他
You destroyed the company.
毁掉公司的人是你
That's definitely wrong.
这么做绝对是大错特错